theappbuilder.com 2014-11-14

# TheAppBuilder | Privacy Policy

The following text is a full statement of the privacy policy of TheAppBuilder Ltd (we, us, our) a company registered under company number NI603525 and with registered address at Unit 2, 405 Holywood Road, Belfast, BT4 2GU Northern Ireland.  
We respect your privacy rights. This policy sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

### INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU

We may collect and process the following data about you:  
• information that we collect from you to enable us to provide our software application TheAppBuilder (our App)to you, as well as information we collect from you during your use of our App. For example, we may collect personal information including your names, date of birth, gender, email, telephone number, job title, company name, and your address. We will collect and store details of your credit card. We also may collect information through any bio details you complete. This information includes personal data as defined by the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act) as amended;  
• information we collect from you each time you contact us, including via our site at www.theappbuilder.com (our site);  
• we may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them;  
• details of transactions you carry out through our site; and  
• details of your visits to our site (including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise) and the resources that you access. 

### INFORMATION WE WILL NOT COLLECT FROM YOU

We will NOT collect and process the following data about you:  
• user location data from mobile applications built using TheAppBuilder (our App), location data will only be used to display user location on 3rd party mapping applications.

### IP ADDRESSES AND COOKIES

We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.  
For the same reason, if you visit our site we may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. They help us to improve our service and to deliver a better and more personalised service. They enable us:  
• to estimate our audience size and usage pattern;  
• to store information about your preferences, and so allow us to customise our site according to your individual interests;  
• to speed up your searches; and  
• to recognise you when you return to our site.   
You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to our site.  
Please note that our advertisers may also use cookies, over which we have no control.  
You can find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, at www.allaboutcookies.org. 

### WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (EEA), including by any member of our group (meaning any parent undertaking or subsidiary undertaking of us, as those terms are defined at section 1162 of the United Kingdom's Companies Act 2006). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.  
Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our app and/or our site; accordingly, by consenting to this privacy policy you are accepting that any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use appropriate procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

### USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION

We use information held about you in the following ways:  
• to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us;  
• to pass to third party app distribution platforms as part of the process of submitting an app on your behalf for distribution via that platform;  
• to contact you to check on your progress in your use of our app, and to discuss any subscription issues;  
• to allow you to participate in interactive features of our app, where you choose to do so;  
• to ensure that content from our app is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;   
• to provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes; and   
• to notify you about changes to our service.  
We may also use your data to provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to you and we may contact you about these by email, post or telephone.   
By accepting the terms of this privacy policy you are consenting to the various uses of your information described above by us. However, if you wish to withdraw your consent, please notify us by emailing us at info@theappbuilder.com. Please note that if you do withdraw your consent we may be unable to provide some or all of our services, and/or the use of our app, to you, and you accept and acknowledge that it is therefore reasonable that we have no liability to you in any such event.

### DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group.  
We may disclose your personal information to third parties:  
• as part of the provision of our app, in which case your information may be disclosed to, or stored by, our service partners (including hosting services suppliers);  
• as part of the best practice operation of our business, in which case your information may be disclosed to our advisers (including solicitors)  
• in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets;  
• if we or substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by us about our customers may be one of the transferred assets; and  
• if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements or to protect the operation of our app and/or our site, or the rights, property, or safety of us, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

### YOUR RIGHTS

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes.  
You have the right to access information which we held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act, and you can contact us at Unit 2, 405 Holywood Road, Belfast, BT4 2GU Northern Ireland. Any access request may be subject to a fee to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.   
You also have the right to ensure that we hold correct and up to date information. If you believe that any information we hold about you is incorrect or out of date, please contact us at our registered address. We may need to ask you for further information and identification to help us to comply with this request.  
Finally, our site and our app may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

### CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on our site and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

### CONTACT

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to info@theappbuilder.com.
